<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Pooja Totlani &#8211; Aadhaar Card Info</title>
	<atom:link href="https://akshaybhopani.github.io/aadhaar-card-info/author/poojatotlani/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://akshaybhopani.github.io/aadhaar-card-info</link>
	<description>World&#039;s largest biometric ID system by UIDAI</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 12:42:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://akshaybhopani.github.io/aadhaar-card-info/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/cropped-aadhar-card-info-main-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Pooja Totlani &#8211; Aadhaar Card Info</title>
	<link>https://akshaybhopani.github.io/aadhaar-card-info</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>when did aadhar card started in india ?</title>
		<link>https://akshaybhopani.github.io/aadhaar-card-info/when-did-aadhar-card-started-in-india/</link>
					<comments>https://akshaybhopani.github.io/aadhaar-card-info/when-did-aadhar-card-started-in-india/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pooja Totlani]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 12:19:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://akshaybhopani.github.io/aadhaar-card-info/?p=87</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The UIDAI was created on 28 January 2009 following a notice from the Planning Commission. On 23 June Nandan Nilekani, Infosys&#8217; co-founder, was appointed to head the project by the then-government, UPA. He was given the newly established UIDAI chairperson post, which was equal to a Cabinet minister in rank. In April 2010 Nilekani unveiled ... <a title="when did aadhar card started in india ?" class="read-more" href="https://akshaybhopani.github.io/aadhaar-card-info/when-did-aadhar-card-started-in-india/">Read more <span class="screen-reader-text">when did aadhar card started in india ?</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://akshaybhopani.github.io/aadhaar-card-info/when-did-aadhar-card-started-in-india/">when did aadhar card started in india ?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://akshaybhopani.github.io/aadhaar-card-info">Aadhaar Card Info</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The UIDAI was <strong>created on 28 January 2009</strong> following a notice from the Planning Commission. On 23 June Nandan Nilekani, Infosys&#8217; co-founder, was appointed to head the project by the then-government, UPA. He was given the newly established UIDAI chairperson post, which was equal to a Cabinet minister in rank. In April 2010 Nilekani unveiled the logo and brand name Aadhaar. Nilekani said in May 2010 that he will support legislation to protect UIDAI data. UIDAI released a list of 15 organizations in July 2010, who were eligible to offer instruction to personnel participating in the process of enrollment. It has also published a list of 220 agencies qualified to participate in the enrollment process. Before this, the initiative was just 20 states and eligible registrars were the LIC of India and the State Bank of India. This launch has taken in a variety of private corporations. It was expected that 31,019 personnel and 155 training centers would be required to meet the goal of enrolling 40 percent of the population in two years. It was also estimated that they would have to establish 4,431 enrollment centers and 22,157 enrollment stations. UIDAI started an online verification system for Aadhaar numbers on 7 February 2012. Using the system, banks, telecommunications companies, and government departments could enter any Aadhaar number and verify whether the person was an Indian resident. Prime Minister Manmohan Singh initiated a direct-benefit payment system related to Aadhaar on 26 November 2012. The project was aimed at eliminating leakages in the system by transferring the money directly to the recipient&#8217;s bank account. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img class="size-medium wp-image-33 aligncenter" src="https://akshaybhopani.github.io/aadhaar-card-info/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/aadhar-card-info-main-1-300x169.png" alt="" width="300" height="169" srcset="https://akshaybhopani.github.io/aadhaar-card-info/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/aadhar-card-info-main-1-300x169.png 300w, https://akshaybhopani.github.io/aadhaar-card-info/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/aadhar-card-info-main-1-1024x576.png 1024w, https://akshaybhopani.github.io/aadhaar-card-info/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/aadhar-card-info-main-1-768x432.png 768w, https://akshaybhopani.github.io/aadhaar-card-info/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/aadhar-card-info-main-1-1536x864.png 1536w, https://akshaybhopani.github.io/aadhaar-card-info/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/aadhar-card-info-main-1-2048x1152.png 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The project was to be launched on 1 January 2013 in 51 districts and then slowly expanded to cover India as a whole. A former Judge of the Karnataka High Court in late November 2012, K. S. Puttaswamy and Parvesh Khanna, a lawyer, filed a Public Interest Litigation ( PIL) in the Supreme Court of India against the Government. They contended the project was being implemented by the government without any legislative support. They pointed out that India Bill 2010 National Identification Authority, passed in the Rajya Sabha, is still pending. They also said that because the UIDAI was only acting based on an executive order released on 28 January 2009, it could not gather citizens&#8217; biometric data, because it would constitute a breach of privacy under Article 21 of the Constitution. In December 2011, Yashwant Sinha headed the Parliamentary Standing Committee on Finance dismissed India Bill 2010 &#8216;s National Recognition Authority and proposed amendments. It called the proposal &#8220;unethical and violative of the prerogatives of Parliament.&#8221; The Supreme Court released an interim order on 23 September 2013 saying that the government could not extend service to someone who did not possess Aadhaar, as the identification number was voluntary.</span></p>
<p>Read More: <a href="https://aadhaar-card-info.com/#update"><strong>A</strong><b>adhar card update</b></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://akshaybhopani.github.io/aadhaar-card-info/when-did-aadhar-card-started-in-india/">when did aadhar card started in india ?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://akshaybhopani.github.io/aadhaar-card-info">Aadhaar Card Info</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://akshaybhopani.github.io/aadhaar-card-info/when-did-aadhar-card-started-in-india/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
